Guide to the Darrin Zammit Lupi photojournalism archive, 2004-2017 RL.11613
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Malta Detention, 2004-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints; 12.57 Gigabytes 1821 files (147 tiff, 1646 jpeg, 20 png, 8 pdf)
  - Large photographic prints, 2006-2013; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 box 20 photographic prints
    - Hands and feet out, 2012 July 17; Legacy id: JM97371 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0039)
      An African illegal immigrant's feet dangle through the window bars at the Safi detention centre in Safi, outside Valletta, July 17, 2012. Illegal immigrants arriving on the island of Malta are detained for up to 18 months, a policy which the United Nations High Commission for Refugees (UNHCR) has said urgently needs a comprehensive review following the death of a Malian immigrant while in custody last month, according to local media. There are currently around 1000 immigrants being held in detention, according to government officials.
    - Sleeping migrants, 2013 October 22; Legacy id: MG_3002 (Box 2, Image RL.11613-P-0040)
      Sub-Saharan African migrants sleep on their beds in a dormitory at the Safi barracks detention centre for immigrants, which currently holds around 650 detainees, in Safi, outside Valletta, October 22, 2013.
  - Low-resolution images (electronic files), 2004-2012; 1646 files (.jpeg); 518 MB
    - 2004-07-25 Safi detention centre (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2006-03-23 Safi and Lyster detention centres (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2006-06-04 Safi detention centre (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2009-01-10 protest at Safi (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2009-03-13 Aerial photos Safi detention centre (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2009-03-14 Barrot visits Lyster (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2010-04-15 Hermes Block at Lyster barracks (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2011-08-17 Court arraignment after riot (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2012-01-20 Immigrants at Lyster (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - 2012-08-18 Bridget Ezukese and Iyahen Sunday at Lyster (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Google Map images of Safi and Lyster (3 files) (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
  - Contact sheets (electronic files), 2004-2012; 20 files (.png); 49 MB
    - Contact sheets for Malta detention centers project, 2004-2012 (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
  - Times of Malta articles with Lupi images (electronic files), 2006-2012; 8 files (.pdf); 3 MB
    - Photo caption: Somali asylum seekers who fled Libya by boat and were rescued at sea by the Armed Forces of Malta and an Italian cargo ship last weekend are seen here at Lyster Detention Centre (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: Iyahen Sunday / Bridget Ezukuse arriving at Haywharf in the early hours of Thursday after being rescued at sea. (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: Behind bars... Aliu Mega (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: 'Please help us...' European Commissioner Jacques Barrot meeting a group of protesters at Lyster Barracks yesterday (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: An immigrant looks out of the police van as he is taken to prison after facing charges in court (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: In a centre where religions co-exist, one wall resembles a Christian shrine with pictures of Jesus, the Virgin Mary and a crucifix / Migrants with nothing to do whileaway their time at the Safi detention centre. (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: Smiles at the detention centre: A toddler seems to be enjoying the friendly tease by one of the immigrants being detained in Ħal Far. / A woman who fled Libya and gave birth in Malta shows off her newborn child from behind the bars at Ħal Far detention centre. (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)
    - Photo caption: Boredom and uncertainty about their future are among the burdens that illegal immigrants face when held in detention centres as they await the outcome of their application for asylum. (Digital-materials RL11613-SET-0006)